翻译　wanderlust　Jalooyt　厨师沙拉
三年前 我醒来后知道了不该知道的事
Three years ago, I woke up knowing things that I shouldn't
字　　幕　　侠
关注新浪微博
@FIX字幕侠
翻译　芋头　希伯来　多星人
ZIMUXIA.CN
校对　多星人　时间轴　iiichiii
然后被诊断为精神错乱
and was declared insane.
原 创 翻 译
中英双语字幕
后期　Jason肖　特效　小布
所以没错 我有秘密
So, yes, I keep secrets.
监制　多星人
但她绝非蠢货 也不是他妈做面包的
She's not a fool, and she's not a fucking baker.
ZIMUXIA.CN
原 创 翻 译
中英双语字幕
拉维妮娅·毕德罗任命寡妇面包师运营慈善之家
攻击三年前就开始了
The attack came three years ago.
这一切是设计好的
This was designed
所以我们仅能管中窥豹 只见一斑
so that we would see the parts, not the whole.
玛拉黛是伦敦最残暴的杀手
Maladie is the worst killer in London's history.
你知道我和谁共事吗
You know who I work with?
是真的吗 你俩肯定是很好的朋友吧
Is this true? You two must be dear friends.
你们俩确实很早就认识 我们都是
Or you do go back a ways. We all do.
它的能量与日俱增 或将毁灭你我
Its power grows by the day. It means to destroy us.
如果我们失去希望...
If we've lost hope...
那说明它已将我们摧毁
it already has.
我要到广场阻止这场绞刑
I'm going to the square to stop that hanging.
我要救玛拉黛
I'm going to save Maladie.
如果要让伦敦于祸乱中幸免...
If London is going to be saved from chaos...
那必须要先出现祸乱
it needs to see chaos.
我确实有使命在身
I do have a mission.
我要寻找"格兰蒂" 按计划行事
I am leaving to find the Galanthi as we've planned.
我们第一步就该了解
It's the first step to learning
为何我们被聚集于此
why we were brought here together
以及接下来我们该如何行动
and what we're meant to do next.
放弃你的名字
Give up your name!
放弃你的渎神之战
Give up your blasphemous fight
加入自由生灵大军
and join the FreeLife Army.
我们是掠夺者 我们是上帝的子民
We are marauders. We are God's Men!
你叫什么名字 姑娘
What's your name, girl?
新兵二号 别动 那就是个喊话的
Second Boot, hold. That's just a Cryer.
拜纳 我们快到了吗
Byner, are we close?
我们就在它正上方
We're right on top of it.
进入点 北侧 20步距离
Point of entry, north side, 20 paces.
新兵 确认进入点
Boot, confirm entry point.
其余人 接替他的位置
The rest, take his spot.
放弃你的名字
Give up your name.
放弃你的渎神之战
Give up your blasphemous fight
加入自由生灵大军
and join the FreeLife Army.
我们是掠夺者 我们是上帝的子民
We are marauders. We are God's Men!
看见什么了
What do you see?
找到进入点了 有个梯子
Found the point of entry. It's a ladder.
看不清有多深...
Can't see how far down it goes...
-新兵 走 快走  -交火
- Boot! Go now! Move! - Contact!
我们突遭火力攻击
We're taking fire.
多名敌人
Multiple hostiles!
稳住 士兵
Steady, soldier.
我们可以慢慢杀光你们
We kill you all, it's gon' be slow.
我们也可以谈谈
Or maybe we could talk about the prize
最初吸引我们到此的战利品
that brought us all here in the first place.
你现在是行星防御联盟的俘虏了
You are now captives of the PDC.
第一章
条纹军
太好了 这里暖和
Oh, my blood, there's heat.
给我把灯打开
Get me fuckin' light.
空气没问题
Air's good.
拜纳 灯
Byner, lights.
整个系统都有门禁
The whole system's gated.
需要硬性连接 雷克斯才能进入操作系统
Rex can't tap the O.S. without a hard connect.
-派小雷克斯  -雷克斯
- Send little Rex. - Rex.
行星防御联盟创造的人工智障
PDC creates A.I., forgets the I.
你们还不是克隆了我们的操作系统
Like your systems didn't clone our O.S.
别听他的 你是个好机器人
Don't you listen to him. You're a good bot.
里面有什么埋伏吗
You got any surprises waiting in here?
鉴于这种情况 我倒是非常希望有
I dearly hope so, given the circumstances.
我们正在追踪空间异常的缘由
We were tracking the source of the spatial anomaly,
和你一样
same as you.
自由生灵大军的灯标标记了这个地方
It was a FreeLife beacon that tagged this place.
我不知道他们进没进去
I don't know if they got inside.
新兵二号 把他嘴封上
Second Boot, tape his mouth.
-先告诉我你的名字  -名字是神圣的 傻逼
- First tell me your name. - Names are sacred, shitto.
我是约瑟夫·威林·格林伯恩少校
My name is Major Joseph Willing Greenbone,
自由生灵永垂不朽
FreeLife for life!
我们不像你们这帮行星防御联盟的走狗一样躲避上帝
We do not hide from God like you PDC dogs.
-我们尊敬...  -新兵 打个招呼
- We honor... - Boot, say hello.
我们是行星防御联盟
We are the Planetary Defense Coalition.
我们准备在此休整
We are taking shelter here.
我们无意战斗 但我们装备武器
We've not come to fight, but we are armed,
被攻击绝不会手软
and will respond as greeted.
条纹军一个人在这做什么
Hey. What's a Stripe doing here alone?
-为什么没检测到她的热源  -她处于假死状态
- And why didn't we read her heat? - She possumed.
她吃了蓝冰球 我看到她吐出来的
She swallowed glazers. I watched her gurge 'em up.
-她的体温肯定为零  -操
- Her body temp must've been nil. - Shit.
你吃了蓝冰球吗
You swallowed coolant pods?
放松点 不然体温变化会粉碎你的器官
The heat change'll shred your organs if you don't relax.
你的胃加敷层了吗
Is your stomach coated?
啡因
Pheen.
我不能给你啡因
I can't give you pheen.
你精神恍惚的话都没法瞄准
You'll never level if you're zoned.
清场完毕 找到了张结构图
All clear. Got a schematic.
乖乖机器人
Who's a good bot?
楼上有动静吗
Anything upstairs?
那就只有我们了 感觉不太对劲
Then we're alone. Which seems wrong.
条纹军还没报上名号
Stripe hasn't called colors.
-你是哪个队的  -四十一地面队 从爱丁堡出来的
- What's your Pride? - Forty-first Ground, out of Edinburgh.
没人能活着走出爱丁堡
No one got out of Edinburgh.
我们有三人做到了 其他俩死在了半路上
Three of us did. The other two died on the walk down.
我们是第十六雹暴者队 D区绿队
Sixteenth Hailstormers, D-field Green.
我们的条纹军被干掉了 你能出任务的话就上
Our Stripe got taken out, if you're mission fit.
她得先调整状态
I need to get her regulated first.
她在那处于假死状态
She was possuming out there.
还有 我腿上中了弹
Also, there's a bullet in my leg.
医疗区的东北部
Sick bay's northeast quarter.
命令如下 新兵们 看好"少校" 并进行全面清查
So ordered. Boots, secure the "Major," and do a full sweep.
拜纳跟我会尝试联系指挥部
Byner and I will try to contact Command.
我从没见过有人在这么冷的温度下进入假死
I've never seen anyone possum in this kind of cold.
我没有别的选择
I was running out of options.
二十名自由生灵掠夺者比你早一小时空降在此
Twenty FreeLife Marauders dropped in an hour before you did.
二十 我们的扫描仪只扫到八个人
Twenty? Our scanners read eight.
一小时够我杀的了
I had an hour.
你当时在那里真幸运
Lucky, you being where you were.
这我可没觉得
Didn't feel that lucky.
-给我啡因 这破玩意儿没劲  -你不能用纯的
- Pheen. Shit is weak. - You get nothing pure.
吃蓝冰球 那不是在装死 那是在找死
Popping glazers? That's not playing dead. That's practicing.
你的异常值等级是什么
What's your PitSid level?
太高了 升不了新月 也不能回家
Too high to make Crescent, too high to go home.
每个人都有异常值 我最多
Everyone has PitSid. I got the most.
你出现时间错乱 往事闪回吗
You get temporals? Flashbacks?
我连当下是否真实都不确定
I'm not even sure this is now.
很好 你可以出任务了 你帮我取子弹
Great. You're mission fit. You gotta jar me.
你要问我的任务是什么吗
You gonna ask me what the mission is?
你们在找"加兰蒂"
You're looking for a Galanthi.
-你是谁  -我的名字吗
- Who are you? - My name?
这问题有点深入了啊
That's a little forward.
我结婚三年 都没说起过我的名字
I was married for three years, and I never told either of them.
得了吧 为这个鸟不拉屎的空间站争得你死我活
Come on. Fighting over a side post in the middle of nothing
就因为你看到了一个... 空间异常吗
'cause you saw a... spatial anomaly,
这就说明有传送门 解释了"加兰蒂"从何而来
which means a portal, which is how the Galanthi came here,
我估计指挥部看到自由生灵的灯标后 就吓尿了
I figure Command saw the FreeLife beacon, lost their shit.
因为离得近 就派你们过来
Sent your Pride in 'cause they were close,
还因为你是孢子
and 'cause you are a spore.
把啡因还给我吧
Can I have my pheen back?
操
Fuck.
专业术语叫"共情能力增强"
And the term is "empathically enhanced."
"孢子"有点冒犯
"Spore" is a little rude.
对 但只有孢子才会找我茬
Yeah. But only a spore would call me on it.
为什么会冒犯到
Why is it rude?
"加兰蒂"不是对所有人下孢子雨的吗
Don't the Galanthi rain spores on everyone?
让他们都变得聪明又可爱
Make 'em all wise and adorable?
孢子是翻译者
The spores are translators.
它们激活头脑中
They activate parts of the mind
理解"加兰蒂"语言和技术所需的部分
needed to comprehend Galanthi language and tech.
别提能不能了
Not that I can.
这种人我都没见过
I've never even seen one.
但它确实拓宽了视野
But it does broaden the perspective.
这些人在建什么
What were these guys building?
-博物馆吗  -这什么时期的啊
- Museum? - When was this even from?
维多利亚晚期 或许是20世纪初
Well, it's late Victorian. Maybe early 20th?
除了士兵 我以前还干过别的
Wasn't always a soldier.
-那些是条纹模拟卡吗  -一大堆
- Are those sim-strips? - Boatload.
让拜纳检查下 他天天呆在模拟器里
Byner can go through them. He lives in sims.
不只是性爱体验器
Not just the fuck-tech.
主要是性爱体验
Mostly the fuck-tech.
别跟我说他还是处
Please tell me he's not virgan.
信仰"肉体邪恶"那些鬼话
All that "flesh is evil" crap.
这是什么
What is this?
每个"加兰蒂"项目都工程浩大
Every Galanthi project is huge.
净水系统 地壳稳定设备 这是...
Pure water systems, tectonic stabilizers. This is...
那些都没实现
None of those are happening.
自由生灵军轰炸了所有据点 杀了他们
FreeLife bombed every site. Killed them.
所有吗 不是有二十多个"加兰蒂"吗
All of 'em? Weren't there, what, 20 Galanthi?
-剩下几个还活着  -可能就一个吧
- How many of them are still alive? - Maybe one.
可能还有更多
Maybe more.
指挥部就不知道这个
Command didn't know about this one.
目前为止 我们也不了解
Well, so far, neither do we.
操 他妈的
Fuck! Heat!
那他妈是什么鬼
What the fuck is that?
把新月叫来
Get the Crescent.
-那就是"加兰蒂"吗  -慢点
- Is that the Galanthi? - Slow.
安静 你可不想唤醒它
And quiet. You don't wanna wake this thing up.
干 这些小屁孩真够神经兮兮的
Damn, those kids are gray.
没事 就是个花园
Hey, whoa, whoa. It's just a garden.
是啊 不过是个农夫女儿的模拟场景
Yeah, no, it's just something out of a farmer's daughter's sim
就这么出现在现实当中
sitting here in real life.
正常得不得了 用真正的食物制造的食物
So normal and usual. Food made out of actual food.
都先别吃
Nobody eat anything yet.
这有扇门
We got a door here.
拜纳 结构图上里面是什么
Byner, what's the schematic say?
显示这里没有门
That there isn't a door here.
是科学小队
It's the science team.
自由生灵军把他们杀了
FreeLife got 'em.
自由生灵军从不掩埋死者
FreeLife don't hide their kills.
或者善后
Or clean up after.
这通风井很深 有东西藏在下面
This shaft goes way down. They were hiding whatever's below us.
另一层吗
Another level?
拜纳 还有其他不该出现的门吗
Byner, any other doors that shouldn't be there?
等等
Hold.
这... 这是...
Is... Is that...
是血 人血
That's blood. That's human blood.
我靠
Fuck me!
上面就是通风井
There's a shaft right above it.
所以他们才把尸体吊在那
This is why they hung the bodies there.
-什么 是在给它喂食吗  -啥 不是
- What, they were feeding it? - What? No.
"加兰蒂"不以鲜血为食
Galanthi don't drink blood for food.
它在干什么
What's it doing?
队员们 冷静 这是厚玻璃
Pride, stay calm. This is fat glass.
子弹只会反弹回来
Bullets will do nothing but bounce back.
我现在记得了
Oh, I remember now.
找到这地方的那帮家伙确实进来了
The boys that found this place did get in.
但没有足够的火力杀死"加兰蒂"
They didn't have the firepower to kill a Galanthi,
所以随机应变了一下
so they improvised.
烧了灯标杜绝意外 免得我们发射核弹
Lit the beacon and got clean, in case we sent nukes.
-干脆杀了这傻逼  -不行 我们已经完全偏离了任务
- Just kill this shitto. - No. We are completely off mission here.
我们被任命去拯救加兰蒂
We were tasked to save the Galanthi,
结果你们朝它开枪 还打到了自己人
and you all shot at it, and hit one of ours!
-她可不是自己人  -别朝上级抱怨
- She is not one of ours. - Don't shrill at a superior.
-我们是在防御进攻  -那不是进攻
- We were repelling an advance. - It wasn't an advance.
-它他妈的就是想握个手  -我们得到的情报
- It was a fucking handshake. - Yeah, we weren't overly briefed
-根本不足以...  -那些血是怎么回事
- on how all this would... - What about the blood?
-自由生灵军为什么要大费周章...  -折磨
- Why would the FreeLife go to all of that... - Torture.
我们看到了尸体 "天才"
We saw the bodies, genius.
不是说折磨小队 那只是手段
Not the team. The team was just the method.
因为"加兰蒂"与他们感情深厚
'Cause the Galanthi bonded with 'em.
关心他们
Cared for them.
最基本的折磨手段
It's basic torture protocol.
先对家人出手
You always do the family first.
真想知道你的名字
I would love to know your name.
他们怎么从"加兰蒂"获取信息
How could they get information from the Galanthi?
宝贝 折磨可不是为了获取信息
Oh, Dainty, torture's not about information.
是希望
It's about hope.
铲除希望的概念
Removing the concept of hope.
我们做得挺对
But we've done all right.
虽然举措有些不妥 但还是找到了"加兰蒂"
We're all running hot, but we found the Galanthi.
而且它还活着
And it is still alive.
这现在反而成了你们的麻烦
Well, now, that's actually your problem.
遭遇的第一秒 我就呼叫了全面支援
I called for a full incursion the moment we met resistance.
谢谢你的情报 大嘴巴
Thanks for the intel, big mouth.
我们也叫了 等等 我靠...
So did we. Wait. Shit...
所以我们头顶六米之上 将会有场大战
So, a full engagement 20 feet above our heads?
核弹四处乱飞
Nuclear bombs flying everywhere.
没人能活下来
We'll never survive that. Nothing will.
除非我们达成一致
Unless we settle the question,
把那玩意杀了 让它脱离苦海
and put that poor thing out of its misery.
关闭该死的传送门
Close the damn portal.
告诉全世界 一切都结束了
Tell the world it's over.
你们能救下很多人
You'll save many lives.
包括自己的性命
Including your own.
我得联系指挥部
I need to reach Command.
这算是贿赂吗
Is this a bribe?
你得帮我
You have to help me.
不用担心 女士
Don't worry, ma'am.
行星防御联盟在此报道
The Planetary Defense Coalition is here.
你还指望什么
What'd you expect?
这东西让他们噩梦连连 你还指望他们为此付出生命吗
They were gonna lay down their lives for something that gives them nightmares?
-他们得明白关键问题  -那到底是什么呢
- They know what's at stake. - Which is what, exactly?
少校为什么说"关闭传送门"
Why'd the Major say, "Close the portal"?
我以为"加兰蒂"过来后就立马关闭了
I thought they'd close once the Galanthi get through.
这个不一样 这个很稳定 很...
Not this one. It's stable. It's...
指挥部认为有队伍协助建造
Command think it's what the team were helping it build.
后援部队吗
Reinforcements?
你认为还会有更多"加兰蒂"过来
You think there's more comin'.
也许那二十个只是前哨
Maybe the 20 were scouts.
也许"加兰蒂"才刚刚开始
Maybe the Galanthi are just getting started.
这能成为我们扭转局势的机会
This could be where we turn the tide.
完成行星防御联盟建立时的使命
Do the job the PDC was formed to do.
还有时间的
There's still time.
谁都不用死
Nobody has to die.
嗯
Yeah.
总感觉有人会死
Feel like someone's gonna.
难以相信我们居然走到了这一步
It's hard to believe we're finally here.
所有人都很感激这所带来的重大影响
Everyone appreciates the gravity of what this might mean.
差不多是所有人吧...
Okay. Almost everyone can appreciate the gravity...
好啦 你想干嘛啊
Okay! What are you after? Huh?
要不你来报告
Do you want to do my report?
我没想到它这么调皮
I never expected such playfulness.
但说实话 小队一直很努力
But seriously, the team have worked hard,
他们值得今天的庆祝
they deserve their celebration today.
像你这样的自由思考者
How does a free-thinking man like yourself
怎么会如此懦弱
get so egregiously split-tailed?
我知道你想离开这里
I know you wanna walk out of here.
还能去哪 这个星球已经完蛋了
To where? The planet's fucked.
我不喜欢"加兰蒂" 但有了他们 我们才能生存
I don't like the Galanthi, but we need them to survive.
如果成千上万的"加兰蒂"从通风井跑出来呢
What if thousands of them come through that rift?
数百万
Millions?
如果楼下那怪物只是个宠物
What if that freak downstairs is just a pet,
只是过来打探情报的呢
sniffing us out?
这是新月的决定
It's the Crescent's call.
他可不想做出那种决定
He doesn't wanna make that call.
他还把你丢在这里
And he left you with me.
那我们把它转移走
Okay, then. We move it.
不行 风暴造成了静态屏障
Can't. The storm is bringing a static front.
稍动一下 你的肌肉就会爆炸
Any kinetic movement, your muscles explode.
好吧 你赢了
You know what? You win.
-我赢什么了  -你想要什么都行
- What did I win? - Whatever you want.
主要能让你振作起来挺身而出 这里的什么都行
Whatever's here that's gonna make you step up and give a shit.
我们的选择不少呢
We've got a great selection.
随便选
Name your poison.
能混搭吗 还是只能选一个
Can I mix, or do I just get one?
我们离胜利就一步之遥
We are this close to winning.
不只是战争 是整个世界
Not the war, but the world.
想想 把这颗行星赢回来 把它变得宜居
Imagine winning the planet back. Making it livable.
洪灾 饥荒 沙尘暴
Floods, famine, terra-storms.
"加兰蒂"可以阻止这一切
The Galanthi can make them stop.
他们在哪儿
Then where are they?
传送门很稳定 他们怎么不蜂拥而入
The portal's stable. Why aren't they galloping through?
-可能是没准备好  -那为何不早点来
- It's probably not finished. - Why didn't they come before?
你那些伟大的智慧恐龙
What about the five billion people
都没来得及救那五十亿人的命
that your great brainosaurs came too late to save?
-他们又不是上帝  -那就别向他们祈祷
- They're not gods. - Then stop praying to 'em.
能拜托你一件事吗
Can you do one thing for me?
你能不能希望我们能成功
Can you just hope that we make it right?
如果必须要打仗 我不怕
I'm not afraid to fight, if that's what it takes.
但必须要有战斗的目的
But it has to be for a purpose.
必须要有意义
It has to matter.
-对你而言  -你不能要求我
- To you. - You don't get to ask that.
-我就是在要求你  -不
- I just did. - No.
你不能
You cannot.
二十八年来 我浴血奋战
Twenty-eight years of slogging through blood and shit
-失望聚沙成塔...  -别跟我扯战争经历
- and towering disappointment... - Oh, don't war story me.
-我也是过来人  -已经把我永久地埋葬在这了
- I've been in it. - has buried me here, likely forever.
我不会为了等救世主而送死
And I am not gonna die waiting on a savior.
你真是固执 觉得我们一定会死
You're just really insistent that we have to die.
因为我们等来的总是这样的结局
Because this close is where we always end up.
这就是我们所有人的归宿
It's where we all fold.
到了这个地步 发生什么变数都太可怕
This close, change is too scary,
即便对那些为之奋战的人来说 也是一样
even for the people who fight for it.
这就是为什么自由生灵军总是赢家
That's why FreeLife always wins.
-他们并不总是赢家  -他们赢得了历史
- They don't always win. - They own history.
不管以什么形式的赢家 拥有俱乐部的人…
One fuckin' form or another, the man who has the club...
这些我都听说过 我知道并非如此
I've heard all of this, and I know it's not so.
因为你有孢子
Because you are spored.
因为我曾是自由生灵军
Because I was FreeLife.
土生土长的
Born and raised.
我做的事 你想象不到
I've done things that you can't imagine.
孢子没有让我变聪明 也没有给我洗脑
And the spores, they didn't make me brilliant or brainwashed.
它们变成了一个问题
They were a question.
结果我发现
And it turns out that
没有什么比一个简单的问题更能击碎这个世界
nothing will crack this world harder than one gentle question.
没错 我希望...
So, yes. I hope...
有更美好的世界
for a better world.
不
No.
完蛋了
Fuckin' no!
只有它死 你才能活
The only way you live is if it dies.
我们必须离开这儿
We have to get rid of it.
你傻啊 你已经达到目的了 它离开了
You moron. You already did. It's leaving!
没有什么后援部队
There's no reinforcements!
裂缝稳定 因为它走的是另一个方向
The rift is stable, 'cause it goes the other way.
"加兰蒂"没有得到支援 它在撤退
Galanthi's not getting help. It's getting out.
不 不 那...
Nah. Nah, that...
哪有这么容易的事
That feels just a bit too convenient.
不
No.
-求求你 别离开我们  -能关闭电源吗
- Please, don't leave us. - Can we cut the power?
一定是雷克斯绊倒了安全阀
Rex must have tripped the safety.
"加兰蒂"把我们锁在外面了
The Galanthi locked us out.
如今他有了充足的能量...
He's got enough power now to...
去往传送门 然后...
To get up to the portal, and... Aah!
能给我个缝口器吗
Hey, can I get a fuckin' Knitter here?
血要流光了
I'm bleeding out!
你说得对
You were right.
结局总是这样
It was always gonna end like this.
新兵 给我趴下
Boot! Stand the fuck down!
-干得好  -是谁装死最有一套啊
- Good man. - Who's the best at playing possum now?
是她
She is.
撑着点
Stay with me.
我不懂
I don't understand.
他们... 他们放弃了
They... They gave up.
-他们放弃了...  -不是的
- They gave up on... - No. Shh.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
看着我
Hey. Look at me.
"加兰蒂"是搬救兵去了
The Galanthi is going back for help.
相信我 好吗
Believe me, okay?
我相信 有希望的
I believe there's hope.
请保持希望
Please hope.
你想告诉我你的名字吗
Do you wish to tell me your name?
H...
第二章
莫莉
这些小甜点真可爱
Aren't those sweet little things?
瓦纳姆
Varnum!
没想到你今天来这么早
Didn't expect to see you at this hour.
他们交代我们早点去清点库存
They've got us in early for the inventory.
这是什么
What are they?
法国糕点 可露丽
French cakes. Financiers.
黄油用量比面粉多 难以想象
Got more butter than flour. Can you imagine?
莫莉 等你聊完
Molly, for the shops by the docks,
把这些送到码头边店里
when you're done.
来 格特说它们和这儿不搭
Here. Gert says they're out of place.
我觉得她说得有道理
I guess she's got a point.
就像小狗和巨型猎犬站一起
Little pups among the hounds.
太好吃了
That's incredible.
我说真的 莫莉
I mean it, Molly.
-简直...  -格特 你这招牌挡了我门口的路
- These are... - Gert, your sign's blocking half my doorway!
-你走开  -你可以开一间时髦茶室
- Get away with ya! - You could have a posh tea room.
这可是个大怪物
Oi-oi. That one's a monster.
是不是有人把它做坏了
Someone cock it up, did they?
茶室
A tea room?
得了吧 等我成家 就给家人吃的小点心
No, it's just a treat for when I have a family.
你能两者兼得
You could have both.
知道吗 面包大 价格就要高
See, you've gotta charge more for bigger.
女士们喜欢大的
The ladies like it bigger.
这位女士懂我的意思
Ah, yeah. This one knows what I mean.
瞧瞧她 脸红得跟少女一样
Look at her, eh? Blushing like a maid.
明天的隔夜面包比我预计的要多
We're gonna have more day-olds tomorrow than I'd like.
-宝宝在踢吗  -就像在跳康康舞
- Kicking? - Ooh, like a musical can-can.
你准备嫁给他了吗
You're gonna tell him yes?
以后可就没有这么好的男人了
You'll not get many offers as good.
-不确定  -你迷上了瓦纳姆
- I'm not sure. - It's Varnum you're mooning over.
他没有钱结婚
He's not got the money to marry.
他有没说过 有钱了就跟你结婚
Has he even said he would if he could?
闭店
他没有做过那种承诺
He's made no kind of promise.
闭店
所以我更喜欢他
I like him the better for that.
莫莉 你得想想你的未来
You've gotta be thinking of your future, Molly.
现实的未来 不是你凭空想象的
Your real future. Not the one that's in your head.
有个事 我女儿珍妮秋天就12岁了
Thing is, our Jenny's coming on 12 this autumn.
我可以让她免费来给我干活
And, uh, I can put her on for no pay.
这样可以省钱...
So it-it's a savings...
我能理解 当然
I understand. Yes, of course.
本来可以让她出去打工赚钱 但是那些工厂...
I could send her out to earn instead, but these factories...
噢 肯定不能让她去工厂
No, of course she'll not go to a factory.
她得来这儿 跟她妈妈一块干活
She has to come here, work with her mum.
我们店还需要有人送面包
The shops still need rolls delivered.
我不放心让珍妮走河边
And I wouldn't send Jenny 'round by the river.
你帮我送面包 我给你一便士
I'll give you a penny to carry 'em down.
-已婚妇女需要点零用钱  -谢谢 好的
- Married ladies need a little pin money. - Thank you. Yes.
上帝有祂的安排 就这样吧
Well, God makes His plans, so here we are.
妈
Ma.
还记得莫莉吗
Do you remember Molly?
我们结婚了
We're married now.
您看上去很好 特鲁太太
You look well, Mrs. True.
劳烦你拿过去
Well, you bothered to carry it,
给她瞧瞧蛋糕
so show her the cake.
-我给您带了...  -大点声
- I brought you... - Louder.
我给您带了结婚蛋糕
I brought you wedding cake.
太腻了
It's too rich.
上次你恢复得更好更快
You got better a lot quicker the last time.
我没事
I'm fine.
你应该收多点钱
Yeah. You should charge more.
毕竟你生不出孩子 只能多赚点钱了
Since it looks like them rolls are all you're gonna deliver.
真的 你已经流了两个
I'm serious. That's two you've lost.
-要是我们家没人传宗接代...  -还能怀上的
- If I'm not gonna have a namesake to take over... - The next one will take.
抱歉这个时候来打搅
I'm just so sorry for the timing.
但是医疗费用
But with the medical bills,
还有他拖欠店里的帐
him being behind on the payments for the shop,
幸好他住的地方是他妈的
the flat's his mum's.
至少你还有地方可以住
So you'll still have a place.
但托马斯欠债累累
But Thomas' debts are outstanding,
你需要再找其他的…
and you'll need to find something...
-等一下再走  -早上好 珍妮
- Just dragging your heels a bit. - Good morning, Jenny.
-早上好  -我迫不及待想告诉你
- Morning. - And here's me dying to tell you
我昨天在大街上看到谁了
who I saw in the high street yesterday.
瓦纳姆·戴尔
Varnum Dale.
瓦纳姆
Varnum.
我以为他升职就调走了
I thought he moved away for the promotion.
他又调回来了
And back for the next.
现在整个办公室都归他管了
In charge of the whole office.
但他还认得我
But he recognized me.
你敢信吗
Can you imagine?
他的马车停在了路边
Pulled his carriage over.
问起了你
Asked after you.
我吗
After me?
他邀请我们去参加暖房 真是贴心
Invited us all to attend his housewarming, sweet boy.
他的妻子已经怀胎六个月了
'Course his wife's seven months in,
对即将要为人父母的家庭 不孕女人会带来厄运
and a barren woman's bad luck in an expectant home,
所以我帮你婉拒了
so I just thanked him for you.
你当初就应该选择他
That's the man you should have gone after.
我之前就这么说
I always said.
你急着赶路吗
You in a hurry?
-你现在很没礼貌  -让我过去
- Now you're being rude. - Leave me be.
没有好转 可能只是伤风着凉
There's no real changes. Probably just wind.
你还好吗
And how are you feeling?
我很好 谢谢
Well enough, thank you.
虽然你生不出孩子 姑娘
We had our troubles with your system, my girl,
但托马斯去世了
but Thomas having passed,
你们没孩子真是幸运
it's a clear mercy there were no children.
幸运吗
A mercy.
你对她非常好
You're very good with her.
她快死了 我不能袖手旁观
She's a dying woman. I could hardly do less.
别妄下断言 亲爱的
Don't write her off too quickly, my dear.
虽然她没法下床
She'll not rise from that bed,
但杀死她儿子的病并没有带走她
but she survived an illness that killed her son.
我了解这种人
I know that type.
靠一口气吊着 百毒不侵
Cast iron all through.
甚至可能比我们都活得久
Bury us all, more'n like.
上帝自有安排 就这样吧
Well, God makes His plans, so here we are.
有时候感觉 上帝在遇见我们之前
Sometimes it feels like God made His plans
就安排好了一切
long before He met us.
我这次不收你钱
I don't need to charge you this time,
但以后…
but, well, in the future...
愿你全家快乐
从水里捞出来的
Came out the drink.
码头的说她在面包房工作
Guys at the dock said she works for the bakery.
叫莫莉什么的
Molly something.
你在这里会没事的 莫莉
You'll be fine here, Molly.
我很怀疑
Yeah, I might not.
第三章
泰晤士河里的疯女人
这是什么模拟器吗
Is this a sim?
一定是自由生灵的科技
It's gotta be FreeLife tech
你们的时间序列设定烂爆了
'cause your temporal sequencing's fucked.
来和我玩
Play with me.
和我回去 萨拉
Back you go now, Sarah.
你在这待了这么久 该懂规矩了
You have been here enough now to know the rules.
他妈的有什么规矩
What are the fucking rules?
这种"圣诞颂歌"的鬼东西
'Cause this "Christmas Carol" crap is so specific
对于第三阶段来说 过于真实了
to my three-term focus.
在这里讲话给我放规矩了
You will keep a civil tongue in this house.
你要对上帝谦卑感激
You will be meek and grateful to God
你带着一身罪降生
that you have been delivered from your own sinful act.
现在我知道规矩了
And now I know the rules.
你好 莫莉
Hi, Molly.
这些约束带让你不好受吧
Sorry about the restraints.
他们不随便给人套这个的
They don't usually do that,
但你让女舍监很狼狈
but you made a mess of the Matron.
我从没见她叫得这么大声
I never heard her wail so.
-我是萨拉  -倒是很直接
- I'm Sarah. - Yeah. That's a straight play.
你能随便把神圣的名字说出口
You can just gift your sacred name,
因为你不在模拟器里
'cause you're not a sim.
你来自他妈的1812
You're from 18-fuckity-12.
你不像其他人那么刻薄
You're not mean like the others.
我们成了朋友 互相倾诉秘密
We become friends. We tell each other secrets.
你知道吗 萨拉
You know, Sarah,
朋友是不会辜负你信任的人
a friend's the one you trust to trust you back.
这个…
Well...
是这样
Yes.
操他妈的碳基生物 你太无趣了
My carbonated fuck, you are gray!
我没有秘密
I don't have any secrets.
I don't have any secrets!
我是条纹军 我执行命令
I'm a Stripe. I go, and I do.
没有人发布命令 我就没有任务
And no one said "go." I got no mission.
我早该死了
I should be dead.
我为什么还活着
Why aren't I dead?
为什么我的手这么… 小
Why are my hands so... tiny?
没事了 宝贝
It's all right, pet. Shh. Shh.
没事的
Shh... Shh... Shh. It's all right.
It's all right.
这几周来了多少个啊
It's how many, the last few weeks?
你知道吗 好几个看着挺正常
Do you know what? Some of them seem fine at first.
正常吗 昨晚来的女孩浑身湿透
Fine? Girl comes in last night soaking wet.
怎么也弄不干 擦了整整一小时
Couldn't dry her off. Toweled her for an hour.
我们得把她送走
Had to send her away,
她比刚来的时候还要糟…
soaking worse than when she first came...
操他妈的异常度 我需要啡因
Fucking PitSid. I need some pheen.
你要是在外面 就不会取笑我了
If you'd been outside, you wouldn't be making fun.
我才不信什么
I highly doubt the Lord Himself
-上帝在你面前化作一道光  -我看得很清楚
- presented to you as a great light. - I know what I saw.
你的话不可信 亲爱的
You're an unreliable witness, my dear.
你可是在疯人院里
You're in an asylum.
-你也是  -这不一样
- So are you. - This is different.
祂看起来像蜻蜓
He was sh-shaped like a dragonfly.
分崩离析的时候又像… 雪花或者火花
And He came all apart like... snow or sparks.
火花
Sparks?
那里有火吗
Was there fire?
还是孢子…
Or spores...?
祂从我头上飞过 然后他们走下来
He flew over me, and then they come down,
我看到一道闪电
and then I saw a flash.
没有声音和烟雾的爆炸
Like an explosion, but with no noise or smoke.
祂就这样消失了
He was just gone.
总有人会相信我
Someone else will believe me.
我相信你
I believe you.
我想知道到底发生了什么
I want to know exactly how it went.
一点火苗就能让整座院子着火
A single spark can set the whole house ablaze.
-特鲁夫人  -合适大小的短裙 能把一盏油灯
- Mrs. True. - An oil lamp can be hidden under a proper skirt
-藏很久…  -阿玛莉亚·特鲁夫人
- for just so long... - Mrs. Amalia True.
-亨得利先生…  -我是科森斯医生
- Mr. Hundley... - I'm Dr. Cousens.
我来为你做身体检查
I'm here for your physical examination.
不好意思
Sorry.
是我名字 我还不习惯…
It's my name. I'm not used to...
还有另一个白人医生轮班
There's another physician making the rounds,
如果不想要我为你检查的话
if you'd prefer a white doctor.
不是 并不是…
No! No. That's not...
你好 科森斯医生 我叫莫莉
Yes. Hi, Dr. Cousens, it's Molly.
叫莫莉就好
Just Molly.
我们开始吧
Let's do this.
你好像并没有感染
You seem to have avoided infection,
尽管泰晤士河脏得要命
despite the Thames' best efforts.
信不信由你 我经历过更糟的
Believe it or not, I've been in worse.
-你来自美国吗  -加拿大南海岸
- Are you from America? - South-coast Canada.
不是 我是…面包师
Or... Yes. Or no, I'm... a baker.
我知道了
I see.
你有哪里不舒服吗
Are you in any pain?
我很虚弱
I'm weak.
我来这的那天
Has there been anything about a light
天空中有没有出现亮光
in the sky, from the day I ended up here?
有人看见 或是有什么新闻吗
Someone saw, or in the news?
这是你跳进河的原因吗
Is that why you went in the river?
-一道光  -我觉得这是我在这的原因
- A light? - No, I think it's why I came out.
有什么人被… 改善了吗
Has anyone been, uh... better?
更聪明... 有同情心.. 或者...
Smart, or... compassionate, or...
算了 没事
You know what? Never mind.
我听起来确实有点疯
I sound like I belong in this place.
他们抢走了我的孩子
They took my babies!
我天天生孩子 全被他们抢走了
I have a baby every day and they take it!
你这么做无济于事
You're just making it worse!
-回你的地下室去  -不 不要
- Back to the cellar for you! - Aah! No, no, no!
不
No!
我记得我做过这事
I've done this before.
-看出来了  -不是这个意思
- I can tell. - No.
不是... 来的那天我预见到了
No. I... No, I saw it the day I came here.
我以为是模...
I thought it was a sim...
-某种症状  -没事的
- mptom. - It's all right.
我帮你缝起来 我需要护士来...
I'm gonna sew you up. I just need a nurse to...
来
Please.
看来你得理解一会儿
It's a lot to take in.
不...
No. No, no.
来自未来的外星族裔给了我们魔力
Aliens from the future gave us magic powers.
他们正盯着我的脸
It was staring me in the face.
过去的几周你见到了很多
Well, you've seen ailments you can't explain
解释不了的怪病 是吗
last few weeks, yeah?
-是的 就在这里 但我也不...  -不疯吗
- Here in the ward, yes. But I'm not... - Insane?
我也不是女人
A woman.
肯定还有其他男性
Well, there's gotta be more.
不是人人都会被孢子影响
The spores don't affect everyone they hit.
我也不知道为什么
I never understood why.
它们通常不会随机赋予人们特殊能力
But they don't normally cause random powers.
肯定是我漏掉了什么模式
There's a pattern I'm missing.
要是能看到相关报道就好了
Wish they'd let us read the papers.
你为什么告诉我这些
Why are you telling me all of this?
-我信任你  -为什么
- I trust you. - Why?
-难道你预见到了某些...  -不 没有...
- Did... did you see something in... - No. No. I...
我不应该信任你吗
Should I trust you?
你觉得我疯了吗
Do you think I'm insane?
可能吧
Maybe.
可能那些外星人疯了
Maybe your alien was.
他们在折磨它
They were torturing it.
我不知道这是不是好消息
I don't know if this is good news.
但你说对了 人们在掩盖这些信息
But you were right. People are hiding it,
但处处都有案例发生
but it's all over.
无人受孢子影响 共情能力增强
No one's spored, empathically enhanced.
也没人来指引我们
There's no one here to guide us.
告诉我们应该改变什么
To say here's what needs to change.
或是... 怎么了
Or... What?
-去你的  -不是 我没有...
- Fuck you. - No, I'm...
不... 去你的 我就是一个错误
No, I... Fuck you. I was a mistake.
像一个笑话 我是条纹军
A mean joke. I'm a Stripe.
我很平庸
I'm not good.
我遇到的事情用现在的词汇都形容不出来
I've got issues you literally don't have names for yet.
可能是我搞坏了孢子
I might be why the spores were shit.
-你知道来者是谁 你也很在乎  -我努力过了
- You know what's coming. And you care. - I did my time!
我一生都在战斗但一点也没...
I spent a lifetime fighting and it didn't make any...
为什么让我来这里
Why would it put me in this?
没错 手无缚鸡之力的身体 真好
Yeah, this doughy little frame. It's perfect.
我的奶子世界一流 但矮得站在椅子后面就看不到
I got world-class tits, but I can't see over a chair.
这身体...
It's a...
是挺美的
good frame.
也没人在使用它
And nobody was using it.
我要逃出去
I gotta get out of this place.
那你至少得少说几句脏话
Then you might not want to say "fuck" quite so often.
顺便把我的吗啡还我
And give me back my morphine.
操
Fuck!
莱斯特说几周就行了
Lester says just a few weeks.
我确实感觉好多了
I do feel so much better.
我想吃他做的饭了
I miss his cooking, though.
做饭的男人
A man who cooks.
做饭的...男人
A man... who cooks.
他说那道光可能是德国飞艇
He said the light might have been a German balloon.
齐柏林飞艇
A zeppelin.
他并不知道上帝怎么了
He doesn't know what's going on about God.
祂要如何给我们使命
How He's gonna give us a mission.
你没说漏嘴吧
You didn't say anything, did you?
我们的事 还有任务什么的
About us, or the mission?
你不必问我的
You don't have to ask me that.
你是我唯一信任的人
You're the one I trust to trust me back.
女士们
Ladies!
我是黑格医生
I'm Dr. Hague.
我对二位早有耳闻 请问哪位是阿玛莉亚
I've been hearing about you two. Which one is Amelia?
阿玛莉亚 莫莉
Amalia. Molly.
那么你一定是萨拉了
Then you must be Sarah.
你...你都听说了什么
What, uh... What have you been hearing?
首先
Well, first of all,
你们二位是... 附魔之人
that you two may be among the... the Touched.
这是人们对近几个月来...
That's what they're calling these people who've...
被孢子影响的人的称呼
blossomed these last few months.
附魔之人
"Touched."
他们早这样叫我了
They called me that already.
萨拉 是这样
I'll tell you what, Sarah,
我在找人去我那
I'm looking for someone to do a special study with
进行特殊研究
at my facility.
我想和你们单独待会儿
I'd like to spend a minute with each of you.
一对一
One on one.
我能先和阿玛莉亚... 待会儿吗
Can you give me a minute with Amel... Amalia?
然后我们俩再单独谈
And then you and I can have our own little chat?
他们告诉我你可以预见未来
They tell me that you can see the future.
不... 只能感觉
No, I... feel it.
很突然 比如我感觉要摔倒了
Suddenly. Like I'm falling down.
当时没有 但过会儿就成真了
But I'm not. And then later, I do.
有一次 我闻到了燕麦蛋糕的味道
Once, I smelled oat cakes,
那天晚上我们真吃了燕麦蛋糕
and we had them that night.
我不愿意多想
I don't like to think about it too much.
会有点疼
It hurts a little.
我也不想研究它
I wouldn't want to study it.
这不是志愿者研究
It's not a volunteer study.
告诉我...
Tell me...
那些光是怎么回事
about the lights.
什么
Sorry?
天上的那些光
The lights in the sky.
就在你来的那一天
When you were admitted.
我什么光也没看到 我...
I didn't see any lights. I was...
好吧 我掉进了河里
Well, I fell in the river.
还是跳的来着 我记不清了
I jumped, I guess. I don't remember.
记不清了
I don't remember.
那是真的吗
Huh. Can that really be true?
-那些舍监都说你直言不讳...  -是萨拉
- The Matron said you were very outspoken about... - It was Sarah.
她当时很绝望 她...
She was terribly upset. She...
她说她抬头看到了上帝
said she saw God in the sky,
没有人相信她
and no one would believe her.
我撒谎了 因为她不停地哭... 而且...
I lied. Because, well, she wouldn't stop crying, and...
她一直缠着我
Well, she never let it go,
我不能告诉她我...
and I couldn't tell her that I...
怪事发生的时候
When the weird things happened,
她说那就证明了有所谓的"任务"
she said it was proof that there was a "mission"?
拜托 别告诉舍监这事
Please don't tell Matron what I did.
我只是希望萨拉开心
I just wanted Sarah to be happy.
有事情可以...
To have something to...
她觉得她在康复
She thinks she's getting better.
不
No.
怎么了
What's going on?
告诉他你看到了什么 他会帮你的
Tell him what you saw. He's going to help.
-做什么  -做什么
- What a to do. - What a to do.
做什么
What a to do.
今天求死要做什么
What a to do to die today.
然后抿一口
And sip.
真好喝
Delicious.
-大声  -大声
- Loud. - Loud.
这就对了 优雅一点
That's right, gently.
-吵闹  -吵闹
- Noisy. - Noisy.
真可爱
Lovely.
大声吵闹的姑娘们...
Loud noisy girls...
-姑娘们...  -姑娘们...
- Girls... - Girls...
放回碗里
Return to the bowl.
拿起餐巾 擦拭嘴角
Take your napkin, and dab.
两边的嘴角 非常淑女
Corners of the mouth, very lady-like.
然后向女主人致谢
And thank your hostess.
真不错
Lovely.
记住 能力不是用来做这事的
Now remember, this is not what this is for.
派对把戏
彭伯顿预科学校一女生 整天都在变换身体颜色
阿玛莉亚
Amalia?
可以进来见评审团了
The board will see you now.
复核委员会表示你的出院听证会堪称典范
The review board said your release hearing was exemplary.
你表现得十分积极 口齿清楚
That you are motivated, articulate,
你还会照顾院内其他病人
that you take care of the other inmates,
至于附魔之人 让我引述他们的话
and in terms of the Touched, you, and I quote,
"你几乎掌管全院"
"practically run the place."
科森斯医生对你更是
There is also an impassioned recommendation
赞赏有加
from Dr. Cousens.
尽管他并非精神病医生
Although he is not a psychiatrist.
-您为何在这 您是...  -毕德罗小姐
- Why are you here, Mrs... - Bidlow. Miss.
发音不错
The voice is good.
完全听不出是屠夫的遗孀
No trace of the butcher's widow to be found.
好像已经换了一个人
It's as if it were another life.
他们在你床下的地板下面
They did find a cache of weapons
找到了你藏匿的武器
under the floorboards beneath your bed,
就在你的听证会期间
during your hearing.
乘他们把餐盘放在一边 我顺走了汤匙
You grab the spoon after they've set aside your dishes.
削尖的汤匙 那是通往自由的第一步
A sharpened spoon, that's your first step to freedom.
除非被他们找到
Unless they find it.
你完全有理由相信你可以通过听证会
You had every reason to expect a positive outcome from the hearing.
没可能的
I had no reason to expect a positive outcome.
你的"转变"告诉你的吗
Because of your "turn"?
你预见到被拒的结果了吗
Did you see the coming rejection?
"我几乎掌管全院" 还不用花钱
I "practically run the place." For free.
如果你对数字敏感 算算这笔账吧
If you have any head for numbers, you can do the lack of maths.
我对数字相当在行
I have an extraordinary head for numbers.
我也知道人们经常会
I also know that people will often do
不择手段
everything in their power
阻止自己得到想要的东西
to keep from getting the thing they want.
想必你几个月前就可以逍遥在外了
I suspect you could've been miles from here months ago.
那我要去哪呢
And where would I go?
这就是我来的原因
That is why I am here.
你怎么想的
What do you think?
我觉得我开始喜欢上这副身体了
I think I am starting to like this body after all.
噢你说这地方
Oh, the place.
太他妈的沉闷了
It's dreary as fuck.
这里边一定全是
And it's definitely filled with the angry ghosts
被害儿童的愤怒灵魂
of murdered children.
毕德罗小姐给你派什么新人了吗
Miss Bidlow give you any new names?
合适的人选
Possible charges?
一个爱尔兰姑娘 她擅长制造东西
Some Irish girl. I think she builds things.
叫派什么的奇怪名字
Not Patience, but something weird.
宗教脸悲伤相 我也不清楚
Sadness O'Religionface. I don't know.
老天 真希望她喝酒
God, I hope she drinks.
我还以为你只会说大话
I thought you were boasting before.
但你可能是最不能胜任这工作的人
But you might actually be the worst person for this job.
不 我会做得很棒
No, I'm gonna be great.
能给大家带来和谐与和平
Gonna bring us all harmony and peace.
第二章
特鲁
派南斯说这边好走
Penance said this was the easy way!
伯蒂·布莱尔跟我说所有士兵
Bertie Blair told me all the soldiers
都被派驻到其他地方了
would be deployed elsewhere!
奥古斯都 别管那钻头了
Augustus! Leave the drilling!
特鲁
True!
抱歉 抱歉
Sorry, sorry, sorry!
他们撤退了
They're backing off!
如果我们没法下去 你得...
If we can't get down there you need...
阿玛莉亚
Amalia!
霍雷肖
Horatio!
搞了半天 你还他妈的嵌在天花板上
All this time, you're still in the fucking ceiling.
现在怎么说
So now what?
我告诉大家 你能救他们
I told everyone you were going to save them.
能拯救世界
Save the world.
你是... 希望
That you're... hope.
但你并不是
But you're not.
对露西来说不是 对玛丽也不是
Not for Lucy. Not for Mary.
还有萨拉
And Sarah?
我俩这组合 真妙啊 结果你完全不动弹
What a team, you and me, except no you.
没赐予智慧 也没什么计划
No wisdom. No plan.
只是一而再再而三地抛下别人...
Just people to leave behind over and over and...
现在就是 我抛下了派南斯 就因为你说"来找我"
I'm doing it now. I left Penance because you said, "Find me."
我抛下了一切来跟你说话 你倒是说啊
I left my heart to come talk to you. Talk to me!
你为什么要躲起来
Why are you hiding?
怎么会走到这步
Why did it go so wrong?
为什么是我
Was it me?
是我... 脑子坏了才搞成这样的吗
Did my... wreck of a brain cause all this shit?
我不知道还能怎么...
I can't think what else to...
我从这个世界醒来
I woke up in this world,
在这具我都适应不了的身体里 谁...
in this body that I can't fit into. Who...
这他妈是谁 我他妈是谁
Who is this? Who the fuck am I?
你就该带妮特过来
You should have brought Knitter.
她有信仰
She believed.
我却摧毁了她的希望
And I took that from her.
她绝望地死去了 还是我带给她的
She died in despair. My despair.
你应该找别人的
It should have been anyone else.
内心尚未破碎的人
Someone not broken.
一个... 更高的人
Someone... taller.
莫莉...
Molly...
你是不高兴我...
Are you upset that I...
你不想听我说吗
Are you upset that I told you?
-什么  -一下子说了太多吗
- What? - Is it too much too soon?
不是
No.
这有点让人心烦意乱
It is upsetting.
所有人的未来变得如此灰暗
The future being so grim for everyone.
但我们把它改变就行
But we'll just change it all up.
你说得倒是简单
You make it sound so simple.
不 这需要努力
No. It's work.
需要一生的努力
It's a life's work.
可能会让我们发疯 可能会害死我们
Like as not to drive us mad, or get us killed.
我们也不知道做得够不够
And we'll never know if we'd done enough,
或是正不正确
or done it right.
但世上还有什么比毕生心血
But what in the world's as rare and nourishing
更珍贵而有效的呢
as a life's work?
在我看来 上帝赠予我礼物
As I see it, God gave me a gift.
作为补偿...
And by way of recompense...
祂又给了我一个礼物
He's given me another.
我们接下来要怎么做
Any idea what we do next?
你想要战争 亲爱的
You wanted a war, love.
嗯 我知道发生了什么
Yes, I know what happened.
-你以为...  -你是唯一一个
- Did you think... - you were the only one
来到这个世界的吗
who hitched a ride?
阿玛莉亚...
Oh, Amalia...
从那小洞穴至今 已经过了很久
This is a long time from that little cave.
我要你... 忘掉这些
This... I will need you to forget.
原来说的是现在
Oh, that part's now.
一切顺利吗
Go all right?
你呢
You?
暴乱
Uh, it was a riot.
-慢点 慢点  -哈莉特
- Slowly, slowly. - Harriet!
慢点 慢慢来
Slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly.
哈莉特 我... 我很抱歉
Harriet! I'm, I'm... so sorry.
我们没救成玛拉黛
We didn't save Maladie.
我很高兴你尽力了
I'm glad you tried.
那是正确的选择
It was the right call.
我没查出敌人是谁
I didn't find out who our enemy is.
但你查出了其他一些事
But you found something out.
是时候告诉大家了 所有的一切
It's time to tell them. Everything.
未来 "加兰蒂"
The future. The Galanthi.
-即将到来的战斗  -嗯
- The fight that's coming. - Feels right.
-马上就要来了  -我知道
- It's coming soon. - I know.
我的名字是和风
My name is Zephyr.
和风·亚历克西斯·内文
Zephyr Alexis Navine.
我很高兴见到你
Well, I'm very pleased to meet ya.
我也是
Me, too.
ZIMUXIA.CN
关注新浪微博
@FIX字幕侠
要命的原型机
Fuckin' prototype.